But it turned to heaven and spoke on the end
Into the nightest touches in through the darkness
And the darkness of the darkness
The darkness of the darkness
The work is finished
The end is ready
Jesus Christ
My life
Oh
Could it imagine
So great emergency
What heart could fathom
Such countless rays
The God of Aiders
Step down from glory
To where my sin
And their eyes shamed
The cross is broken
I am broken
The King of King's false me
Jesus
Beautiful Savior
The God of Aver
Jesus Christ
My life
Oh
So great
How they do
Yeah
Praise the one
You set me free
How they do
Yeah
So has lost its grip on me
You have broken
Everything
There's salvation in your name
Jesus Christ
My life
Oh
And how they do
Praise the one
You set me free
How they do
Yeah
So has lost its grip on me
You have broken
Everything
There's salvation in your name
Jesus Christ
My life
Oh
So great
How they do
Yeah
So is it
You set me free
How they do
Yeah
So has lost its grip
God of Aiders
Jesus Christ
God of Aver
Oh
So has lost its grip
Yeah
God of Aver
Oh
So has lost its grip
It's sink then came to morning.
Then came to morning.
And there's still the frown is your very body began to breathe out of the silence.
The roaring lion,
The clever grave has still great my way.
Jesus, he was,
It's still great so way.
Oh, the same,
Hallelujah.
Praise the Lord,
You said,
Hallelujah.
That has lost its grip on me.
You have broken everything.
That salvation in your name.
Jesus Christ,
By living.
Oh,
Hallelujah.
Praise the Lord,
You said,
Be free,
Hallelujah.
That has lost its grip on me.
You have broken everything.
That salvation in your name.
Jesus Christ,
By living.
Oh,
Jesus Christ,
By living.
Oh,
Lord,
That you are.
Hallelujah.
Beloved Jesus.
We worship you,
we expressed our.
This place that's set up altogether once again.
And Hallelujah,
Praise the Lord.
Lord.
This salvation in your name Jesus Christ, my living home Jesus Christ, my living
home God you are our living home God you live, let's give God the best God, yes Jesus, we worship you,
testify
when we make God the world Christ
God is our refuge,
Asinasa binye posse nyung sari ta sa san chaptor 46 verse 1
God is our refuge and strength and ever present in time of troubles.
I am in Kandungan, am in Kala Kasan,
at Laddinghandang to Moulong, Sapana Hon, Nangkaguluhan.
Many of us have been in the state of the Church of the Philippines.
We have been in the state of the United States for the first time in the world of the United States.
We have been in the state of the United States for the first time in the world of the trustees.
Our struggle for his food bodies is suitable for injury.
MyHI then served in the United States,
as a successful refugee, the United States and our host,
Seannie
Minister Heathraz,
,
oh
be
leaders, go in moon lugar ambawat groupo para sapa glagot sapa nannam palataya
disahi polsheep panalangin pagmama halan begamonang wisdom and grace ambawat
leader pagpala in moan lahat nang boluntir sabaot ministry at palakasin sila saka
nelang pagli din kod. Amah i pinapan nannamin angbilipinas i nannam muka misa
mga halanidan tulad nambagyo bahan din do lan slai pagputok nambulkan
matinding init at i papang sakuna. Begin moanang kar nungan amanganamumuno amang
reschewers medical workers volunteers at lat nang tumutulong sapa nang kalamidad
pangin oon pinapan nelangin amin ang aming bansa at pah mahalan
began moanang wisdom and grace ambawat groupo para sapa nang boluntir sabaot
nang lahan nang boluntir sabaot pishal saharat nang boluntir sabaot
rabshon at maling paggamid nang kapangirihan pai ralimo ojo sangkatatohanan
katarungan pana nangutan at katapatan hipu imo ang pusunang baubat nang
mumuno u pangpili inang tamah at maling kod nang kapat sainyo
nang kar ona wasi langang nang tumay nang harlungan sabaot katang simulang
nang karlungan ayang pakatakot sainyo mulasa executive legislative and judiciary
ipin nangin dinamin ang pishan order sabaot sahaminko menidad sahamink li punan
mangatahana nang pakaralan workplace barang guys lung sodabung li punan
ileumokuin sakara karahasan krimen pang aabuso gali at pakahati hati
turun turun anmokamimamuhay nang maitang ibi respeto at pakpapatawad
pangin onin ilalatit nangin sayo anbawat pamilya at komenidad
ikam nang wawat ang maging sain turun anm bawatahana nang pak isahin
nang mangamag asaawat palakasin ang relasion nang mga gulang at nang
mga anang at mga bgay nang probision protection at pish sabaot panilla
gamitin moing ibleasha u pang maging pakpapala sabaot komenidad
ojo si panalang nangin amin amin pung iban jalis in airport
disipul ship and leadership began development began muka minang pusung ni malasakits
samangain di panahakila alasainyo tulu ngan mo ambawat ming buronam makaeronang i sang
taung ipinapanalang nila nila latit nila latitan nina at inahakai kekri sto
gamitin moing amin peig groups outreach u pang maraming buhai ang mga abot nang
inyumabutin balita pangin oon sina sai bimose sam chapter 46 burst ten
best till and know that i am god sagitna nang kaguluhan tulu ngan mohaming mana
mana himik makti wala at kila nani nakekong jos kapak meitahot i kawakamin kapa
yapa an kapa mainang nina ikong amin kala kasan kapa gindin amin alam ang susunit
nakbang ikong amin gabaay nabai nag gamitimuo ang ibleasha yitong chus nato u pang luma go
nang sama sama magling kod nang sama sama at maa abot ang lahat nang tau
nang sama sama para se nyung i ka lulu alhati
the lord almatis with us the god of Jacob is our fortress
sa pangalan nang anting panginong ang susunitong
amin te gaba ginditasa pangin oon kami ain nangan alamin
mga temak sabinang aiman
morning poor
ah on behalf of the co-opoles of faith
mga dkuma agapus alhat make link announcement
long poor we at co-opoles of faith has an evangelistic project called kasa alang bayang
siguro pamilar ka doon satem nakasa alang bayang ah
this is the highlight of our event on November 7th, 2022
this would be a Saturday 2 to 5 p.m.
the purpose of this project is ultimately to give honor
to our god by encouraging copoles
to make their relationship right not only in dyes of man
but also in dyes of god that's why we are inviting
interested copoles who wanted to get married
and to be part of this kasa alang bayang event
okay this is a legitimate wedding to be officiated
by our senior pastor en nyung hilario
so in dpui to is kama in dpui to kasa alang kasa alang
it's a po ai legitimate wedding event
so since it's a November 7th
you still have enough time to process
you did me successful
teacher
my
remember
my former
Okay, so since this is a couple of faith events,
we are giving an instant honeymoon gift.
Wow.
So the participants think of calls such as an overnight hotel accommodation
and doing say the past, you go to dinner for two.
Okay, so
So the participate is an interesting wok.
What this is called is the Main Event
which will be held at the table saw above
the highest command of thecream in the city left strides to the event.
If you have to submit a welcome,
All bring your own sponsors up the words,
but they can't celebrate, no, sell a bus.
Okay, that's a button that's a plus,
a plus, put a screen for those couples who are interested.
Please contact C or call pastor Ed Santiago at Nakumali,
it's a number, but we're going to read it.
In 1907, 873567.
We're going to read it, we're going to read it,
we're going to read it, we're going to read it,
and other community pastors.
We've been helping us since May.
May Papuna, I'm going to ask you a question,
how community is to find interested couples,
but up to date, no find.
Papuna, I'm going to ask you a question,
what's interested in us?
We're going to read it, we're going to read it,
and set up.
So please look and see call pastor Ed Santiago at 0.97873567,
on or before next Sunday, that would be September 27,
26.
So, I'm going to read it,
and date Puna Castle, I November 7, Saturday,
the Du Po Ang Vanu, Sanctuary, and Oraspo,
I 2-5 p.m.
Okay, so, in the past few years,
I was going to ask you a question,
what do you think about this,
when you're in a Bosco,
I'm interested in what you're going to do,
or what you're going to do,
to make your relationship right, not only in the ice of man,
but also in the ice of God,
I got less support, I got less support, thank you,
Paul.
Thank you, Chris, that's a wonderful good news for all of us,
Castle and Bahia, so,
some of our public, John,
and our UIA available, or those of you who are interested,
it's a wonderful opportunity for you guys
to take advantage of what we are offering us at church,
and as he mentioned,
Merrick Maeropuma, I'm going to ask you a question,
and we do hope that you do connect with your community pastors,
with pastor Ed, so that you will know more about what you can do,
in order to join us,
to the Po Saatin Castle and Bahia.
By the way, this would have been the second time
that we will be doing this as a church.
This is a ministry that we want to do
in coordination cooperation with the Co-opulse ministry.
Now, what is the point, you take advantage?
Now, Patulina Putay, I'm going to ask you a message,
previously, we have talked about what Jesus has done for us,
and how it can change our lives.
Through Jesus, we have been brought to God,
and we have been brought to each other.
We belong therefore together.
This is still a part of our year-long theme,
growing together, reaching together.
And today we will continue on with that message.
But this time, we're going to make it a bit more specific,
more practical, and actually more personal.
Anubang, it makes a behind when we say that we are actually
called to live life together.
What does it mean for us to grow together?
How do we reach others together?
And how should following Jesus change the way we treat one another?
Today, we're going to look at some simple,
very practical ways we can live this out.
So I hope that you are ready.
If you say you are ready, can you say, I am ready?
All right, and I hope that you are in the ready,
because today, Paul McGeeging, practical,
young, I think, Pagu, Sapa, and how we can grow together.
Now, I'm Pina Kaesan, Spock.
Now, message not in today's list,
because of God's grace and mercy and Christ,
we are transformed from a self-centered life
into another centered life,
where we recognize that we belong to one another.
So first, let us see how this came to be.
But Anubang, Tornang, Yaris,
Aten, Unapusalat, the Gospel, Transformsus.
Tayumunai binagunang, Panginong, Dios, Romans chapter 12,
verses 1 to 3.
It says that, therefore, I urge you brothers and sisters
in view of God's mercies to offer your bodies
as a living sacrifice, holy and pleasing to God.
This is your true worship,
do not conform to the pattern of this world.
But be transformed by the renewing of your mind.
So Sinabidito Nipablo, when he wrote to the church,
Dahl Sabiayanapanginong, Dios, Dahl Sabag,
Somersinaapanginong, Dios,
we are called to live a life of true worship.
Now, the kind of worship that Paul was talking about
is beyond the worship that we do on a Sunday,
where we come together as a church,
we lift up our songs of praise and worship to the Lord.
It is part and parcel of it.
But the true worship that Paul was talking about
is the worship that we do in our lives
to offer our lives to God as a living sacrifice,
holy and pleasing to Him.
So in Bhagipi-gaynaatena papurihindilama sabosesindilama satinig
when it's acting buhai.
Hayang Sabidito Nipablo, do not conform to the pattern
of this world but be transformed by the renewing of your mind.
Angnais naapanginong, Dios, he is calling us
to transformation, not conformation.
Angnais naapanginong, Dios, Taiyo, Ayma, Bhago.
As the original, Salitan conform,
it raises back to that world which means to shape,
to fashion or to fashion after.
Yibig Sabinong, Hino, Hu, Bo, Ayon, Don, Sashap,
or Shave, Nang, Ating, Gina, Gaya.
To conform to the world therefore means allowing the world
around us to shape us, to think, act and live like everyone else.
Hayangibig Sabinong, conformation to the world.
Yibig Sabinong, Taiyo, Ayhino, Hu, Ma, Bina, Bina,
Gona, Teño, Ating, Hu, Gis, Or Taiyo, Bina, Bago,
Yong, Ating, Hu, Gis, Or Wang, Ion, Sa, Shave, Nang,
Mundo, Ito.
The opposite of conformation is transformation.
Angpinagmumulana manito es Sangsalitanayibig Sabinisa,
Bhaguhin Anghu, Gis, to change the shape of.
Bhag-Cinabing transform Bina Bago, Yong, Hu, Gis, Bina Bago,
Yong, Wang, Ion.
Very untransformation, Abina Bangitni, Pablo,
Siroma's chapter 12, Hindi Lampu Yong, Hu, Gis, Angkaniang,
Bina Bago.
The transformation that Paul was talking about in Romans chapter 12
is a transformation from the inside out.
And so therefore this transformation begins in the mind.
Sabinisa Romans chapter 12 verse 2,
do not conform to the pattern of this world.
But be transformed by the renewing of your mind.
Angpagbagbago in Xe-Simula, Sapagbago, No Ating, Aisypun.
And what we believe shapes how we think,
and how we think influences how we live.
That's why our God does not only want to change what we do.
He wants to renew the way we think.
That's why we think about the way we think,
and we think about the way we think about it.
So from the inside out, God changes us through Jesus Christ.
And because of what Christ has done in us,
our lives, therefore should become different.
Jesus did not save us, so we could simply fit in.
In the same time, we think about the way we think.
He is transforming us so that we can stand out and reflect him.
And Izana Sapina, Camarque,
and Transformation, Aito, Aia, Melitee,
one of the Marx of Transformation is humility
and verse 3 of Romans chapter 12 says,
do not think of yourself more highly than you ought.
But rather, think of yourself with sober judgment.
Now, Hapagbina Sanyu, poem verse 3 and Romans chapter 12,
you will recognize that Paul again brings back
other his readers or his listeners to the aspect of how you think.
Aunanyam Sina, be you must think of yourself more highly than you ought.
But Mooda O'Isi Pina Saryli, monamasigitpa,
Sana Rara, but to be transformed to becoming humble,
the first way of thinking is that we must avoid pride
and exaggerate the view of ourselves.
Instead, let us focus our way of thinking
into the second part of thinking that Paul would say there.
In this number, he seeped with the high view of ourselves,
we should think of ourselves with what with sober judgment.
So, Delawang Aspeto, Ankai Sipan, Dapatnating Baguhin,
Indima Karonama Padmatas, a pride for a proud way of looking or thinking of ourselves.
Whether at the same time thinking of ourselves with sober judgment,
in simple terms, don't think that you are more important,
more valuable or better than others.
See yourself honestly at humbly before a God.
And so instead of having a very inflated, independent, exaggerated view of ourselves,
we are there for have to have a sense of need of each other.
Iwiqsa Bhianyum Faukus Muq, Dapatmababaguddin,
Kapaktaaydin at transform Makakar Onahm transform Meishan.
So transform Meishan from the inside out.
At you inside out transformation begins with the way we think.
And when we think according to God's ways,
we are transformed into becoming humble men and women of God.
Now this humility may boom up again.
This transformation changes us from Me to We.
The transformation to humility,
dahil Hindini Nani Nani Sari Linnatin,
with such a high degree of regard.
This transformation to humility results in recognizing,
therefore, that we are members or parts of the body.
Hindiparasasaril Ilanang, Hindii Sari Linnatin,
Kundi connected sabawati sa.
So in Christ, we though many for one body,
and each member belongs to the others.
When we have a high view of ourselves,
some of shoot notice, some result
and notice that we would think of ourselves as probably independent.
Haya Natin, Gawin, Ambaat, Lahat,
we might most likely have a very self absorbed
and involved instead of recognizing our need
belonging to others.
Often, a high view of ourselves thinks this way.
If we look at ourselves,
we can see that we are not going to be able to do that.
We are not going to be able to do that.
We are not going to do that.
That's often what a high view of ourselves looks like.
Instead of looking at ourselves also as needing something.
So in this way, we are not going to be able to do that.
But in Dina, Iis, if Naito, Ika, Ilaman, Natin.
It is the transformation that Paul was talking about
from a very selfish, self-centered view
to another centered view.
Antahuan, Pune, Natin, Dito, one another, Christianity.
Natin, Natin, Ambaat, Issa, Nama, Lahat,
remember what we spoke about last week
that Jesus brought us to God and brought us to each other.
We recognize therefore that we belong to another
but by all of it, one other Christianity, how does this look like?
Paul then would show us what this one another Christianity
look like in our relationships.
Dito, Napoti, Tignan, Natin, this is where we will be very practical.
And one another Christianity is a life of,
Bessayin Pune, Natin, it's a life of love.
Napoti, Nasa Natin, Romans chapter 12, Paul will now
start talking about love.
Now the love passage or the love verse that we are often
acquainted with are Jung Nasa first Corinthians.
But this in Romans chapter 12, Paul would speak about the many ways
where we could actually demonstrate what love is.
What loving one another looks like, Ito'atin pagaral ngeyona,
at this point, I would like to call again everybody's attention.
I like for you to pay attention because we are going to be very practical.
And I want for you to specifically think of how you can apply
today's message.
Sabipu Jan, one another Christianity is a life of love.
Nantanong, Anubayung is Sangbuha, Naka kakitā Anang pagmībīg,
atpā anubayung to Madhidemonstrate Sabawat isa, ilam bhagipu,
angustokum pagusāpan based on Romans chapter 12.
Ilam bhagayung, nama kpāpahi wateg, ways were in we could demonstrate
what love is as a mark of one another Christianity.
Una pusalaat, one another Christianity or loving one another is serving the Lord
and one another.
Can we read that first line?
Love one another is serving the Lord and one another.
Now, familiar probably, can you do in the five love languages?
Limayon, I'm sad.
Una, I am words of affirmation using unspoken or written words,
giving compliments to our loved ones or appreciation.
Isa doyansa, five love languages.
I am a law-m'love language I receive in gifts valuing the thought or effort
and symbolic meaning.
Now, is some tangible way, I am a love language I have put bebegayung,
I am gift or Patangapna, who among you love language and receive in gifts.
Marais al-Satini say in Sama-gabagayna,
Guestunatini.
Another love language is called quality time.
We just want to spend time with each other.
Another love language is called physical touch.
Now, affirmation with the tap on the shoulder or with our loved ones,
when we meet with them or when we hug and when we spend not just time,
but when we express our love through physical intimacy,
la luna punta, yu, ay mag asa, wa.
Now, hey Kalimak act or love language, I am acts of service.
And this way of love language, pinapahitamongyupagibig
by doing helpful tasks or chores that lie to your partner's physical or mental load.
Yeah.
So, yu mga love language, I service silayung magi magi magi, magi nis sabahai.
Silayung magi, magugas langpiggan, silayung ina ayos yu kane lang kwartopagising nila.
Silayung magi nis da mga pinaglutua nimesis pinakayin na nangmanganak.
They are the ones that are actually able to show their love language by serving.
Now, silayung magi naburi to jis as show us what this love language looks like.
Jesus was sent to k, he came to serve and not to be served.
And as his followers, we are simply following the example of jis as Christ.
Now, in the church, one important way we love one another is by using the gifts that God has given us to serve others.
So, I will be putting this to Romans chapter 12.
We have different gifts according to the grace that God has given us.
If it is serving, then serve, it is teaching, then teach.
If it is to encourage, then give encouragement.
If it is to lead to it diligently, if it is to show mercy, do it carefully.
Now, it is a moment of spiritual gifts that the Bungit's Romans chapter 12.
It is not an exhaustive list of spiritual gifts, enablement of panginongdhyos.
Masmarami papung binigayna biaya panginongdhyosabawat isa.
But on nice and too early Pablo, what Paul is trying to teach is that if we want to show love to the church,
we serve.
You show love to each other in your faith groups when you serve one another.
You are allowed to breathe together.
You are not afraid, first, orкая.
Welcome to another episode of Fried WMP Donut Freedom Brutary.
A board of elder members, Sinoma, board of elders and Ari,
to the young generation there you go.
We have some of them.
We have a board of elders,
board of elders, board of elders.
Now, you are the one who is the youngest,
but the youngest.
Sinopuriti, the young, the elders, or the leaders.
Can you raise your hand?
Are you?
Asa, likuransilah, asihandasilambat ashir, at Magrid.
Now, Sinoma, Ditoon, the young,
the worship department, Pakitas, Ghan, Khamayn.
And Ditoon, Sila Sahara, Pana, Ditoon,
Sattahas, Member, Numbers,
The Department, Yung, Atimaga, Teachers,
Secrets, or probably their downstairs,
your teacher, Razer, Han.
Now, we also have the counseling ministry,
asa, and Bihmati, Maga, Khamasilers.
You may want to raise your hand as well.
Praise the Lord.
He to Mahala Ghadil.
Yung, Maga, Pastor, Naten, Pedi,
Bang, Pakitas, Khamayn.
Naman, Pastor.
Praise the Lord.
All of us, or all of you,
that are serving the Lord in the church,
until the two were in Romans chapter 12,
that's how you are showing love.
In the name of God,
in the name of God,
in the name of the Lord,
when you serve.
Now, I'd like to just further encourage all of you.
Mayu Pusina, Bishipol,
Sarova, Chapter 12, verse 11, Sabinyapudito,
never be lacking in zeal,
but keep your spiritual,
further serving the Lord.
To those who are showing love to God,
and to each other, by serving,
Hanksang, encourage Puri Pablo, is this,
never be lacking in zeal,
but keep your spiritual,
further serving the Lord.
Never be lacking in zeal,
simply means,
O Khamma Ghing Pabaya,
Dunat Bikam, lazy,
Dunat Bikam, careless in serving,
and then Khamang, Kabalik Taran Panorang,
encourage,
and no positive, exhortation,
and you, Paul,
is for you to keep your spiritual,
further.
So, O Khamma Gpabaya,
to the point that you will become lazy,
or lacking in passion.
Instead,
I'm Sabinyapudito,
keep your spiritual,
further.
Now, Pina Galinga Pupina,
Galinga Pupina,
phrase,
now, to keep your spiritual,
further,
the analogy of keeping your spiritual,
further is that of boiling water.
Isangtu Bikna Kumukulok,
Hindi Mublang,
Hindi Mubas Tapas,
Hindi Mublang Pina Kukulok,
one that has a spiritual,
further and serving to God
is like water that is boiling.
Nagi ma'init,
at nakakita,
usso or konganuman,
you are able to see how exactly passionate a person is
in having a boiling water as an analogy,
Kumukulokluungtu Bik,
I beg you,
be in,
Mahinit,
Hindi Mubaksa Biksa Bikhin,
Maligam Gham,
Ayapala,
Siddhi Jesus Christ,
Asina Sabinyas,
Sinusukanyah,
Angmungat, O Sinabinyah,
Napa Pagyabhinah,
Tse Panginun,
Ayapala,
Imaigam Gham, Ito Ay, Sinusukanyah,
Dailyam na is nangpanginun dios,
Daayamakar O nangganu uri nangpashan,
Ayapala,
serve on excitation,
Nepal,
Asservants do not be luquar,
but instead be boiling hot.
Because the reality is our passion to serve,
can diminish.
We can get tired.
We can get discouraged.
We can become too busy.
We can become disappointed.
Sometimes,
serving simply becomes a routine.
And slowly,
we can lose our zeal and spiritual fervor.
But Paul reminds us of something important.
Taayu ahindi lamanakshisil misabawat isa.
We are actually serving the Lord.
Ultimately, we are serving Jesus.
Yes, we serve people.
Yes, we serve the church.
But behind every person we serve,
we are serving the Lord.
So don't just serve the Lord half-heartedly,
serve with eagerness.
Serve with passion.
Serve faithfully.
And perhaps,
sometimes kala nangadinateen ai bahaji bhane wa wa laayu ating zeal
at passion to serve the Lord.
And more importantly,
what do I need to do to keep the fire burning,
whatever it may be,
don't just keep serving while your heart grows cold,
come back to Jesus.
Let Him renew your heart
because we don't simply want to be busy serving Jesus.
We want our hearts to burn, to boil, to burn as we serve Him.
So keep serving, keep growing, keep the fire burning.
So loving one another means serving.
The second one.
Loving one another is sharing and blessing one another.
I'm sorry, people, this is a Romans 123.
Share with the Lord's people who are in need, practice hospitality.
Bless those who persecute you, bless and do not curse.
Now one way that we show that we love one another is by sharing what God has given us.
And there are three ways where we could share.
We could share what we have.
We could share our home.
And we could share gracious words that long para anam pañ share at pag bless.
Una sharing what we have.
We share with the Lord's people who are in need.
A pag may repeat time of our brothers and sisters.
La Luna posa faith group or sister in need.
We don't simply say, I'll praise, I'll pray for you.
We also ask is there something that I can do to help.
Maybe someone needs food.
Maybe someone is struggling financially.
Maybe someone needs transportation or some other practical help.
God bless us, not only that we can enjoy his blessings, but he also bless us so that we can
become a blessing to others.
So ask yourself, is there someone in my faith group, church or circle of relationships
in your family who has a need that God is calling you to meet or to address?
Maybe it's a material way of sharing.
Now I suppose Bala won't be in a guitni pablorita sharing your home.
Practicing hospitality.
It may not be something that we would have expected as a way to share.
Hospitality is simply opening our lives and making room for others.
Now it doesn't require an atintahana, an amaganda.
It doesn't require a beautiful house or an expensive meal.
Sometimes it's simply saying, come over, let's eat.
Let's talk.
It evacutes the sense that many lives have a sixteenth day.
You requested me to cross Pagsilbee between our parents from the village
for you to be another I love you.
I believe明ele has a time for your presentation.
first time, I realize that it's not really necessary to welcome people at your home.
At Akomi's one about Guobi Lampili Pino.
I remember the time when we were invited to a relative of the home of a sadrace relative.
And it was about close to I think dinner time.
The Shemprek Amangapili Pino, Kampag Malapit Nasa dinner, Agina Andamo, Pangdino, no?
Thank you so much, Lord.
All they had was tea and some cookies.
And then I told myself, it was not necessarily so.
These people are opening their homes to us and welcoming us.
Whether they had something to offer in terms of food
that we could eat or not.
That is when I have come to a realization
that you just simply need to open your doors to people
and practice hospitality yourself.
Yes, if you have something to offer,
invite them to eat, but more than anything else,
when you open the door of your home,
you are allowing them to enter in to your life.
You see, our homes can be complacent
where people experience love.
They, as those are places when they could feel heard.
And courage, this cycle, or cared for,
so tired and tired to go on.
Now, if you go to your house,
it's not suitable enough to be open
to be to practice hospitality
because you have nothing to offer, put that aside.
Others just simply want an opportunity to be welcome
into your home that they feel that they are becoming apart.
So, not enough powerful when we open our homes to others.
So, we love and we show that we love one another
by serving, pangalawa by sharing.
Pangatlu, I sharing is sharing materially
pangalawa opening our homes, sharing our homes.
There's a third way when we could share,
we could share words that bless.
Now, so, we do some verse 14,
bless those who persecute you and bless and do not curse.
It's a love language in the Bagi-kukanina,
our words of affirmation.
Words are powerful.
Words can be shared to bless others.
Words can hurt.
Words can heal.
Words can discourage.
Words can encourage.
Words can tear down and words can build up.
Now, see Paul, he goes even further.
We are not only called to bless those people who we love,
or people who are good to us.
Notice how extra, Paul is calling people,
the kind of an extra mile that Paul is calling people to do.
We are called to bless those who hurt us,
bless those who persecute you,
bless, do not curse.
So, instead of returning hurt for her,
criticism for criticism, or angry words for angry words,
Jesus is calling us to respond differently,
speak words that give grace,
speak words that encourage, speak words that bless.
And that's what one Christian,
or one another Christianity looks like.
We share, we share what we have,
and often, materially, we share our homes.
We open them to others, and we share words that bless.
Because when we understand that we belong to one another,
what God has given us is no longer about me.
So, one another Christianity is loving one another,
and we are not going to be able to do that.
We are not serving, we are not serving.
We are not serving, we are empathizing.
We are empathizing with one another,
rejoicing with those who rejoice,
mourn with those who mourn.
Christian love means entering into what other people
are going through.
We don't just live beside one another,
we share life with one another.
I'm sorry, Puri Pob, rejoice with those who rejoice.
Now, Medjo, it's in the Mahirab,
the Mahirab is not a Mahirab,
but it's not a Mahirab, but a Mahirab is not a Mahirab.
It means that we are not appropriate,
but we are not going to be a part of it.
It's easier for us to rejoice.
But we are not going to be together with God.
We are going to be together with God,
and we are going to be together with God.
But when we find people that have something
worth celebrating, we celebrate with them.
When someone gets a promotion, celebrate,
when someone's prayer is answered, celebrate.
When someone succeeds, celebrate.
When God blesses someone, celebrate.
Sometimes it's not very easy because
when we are not going to be together,
we are not going to be together with our blessing.
Because when someone receives blessing,
something or receive something,
we have been praying for ourselves.
We can begin to compare Lord about me.
You know, we are not going to pray for ourselves,
but you know, God.
You know, God is going to be a Lord.
So why amenestry?
You know, God is not a single Lord.
You know, God is not a single.
I know God is not a progress.
That is not the way it is.
You know, God is not about me Lord.
Or, you know, God is not going to be a Lord.
You know, God is not going to be a Lord.
And then they got it, but I did not.
But genuine love says,
your blessing may not be my blessing,
but I can still celebrate with you.
When we truly love one another,
we don't compete with each other.
We celebrate each other.
Then Paul says, mourn with those who mourn.
We are not going to pray for the Lord.
Because we are not going to pray for the Lord.
When someone is hurting, hurt with them.
Sometimes we think that we need to have the right words.
We want to explain away what is happening to them.
Sometimes we feel the need to give advice
to solve the problem or repeatedly make the person feel better.
But sometimes people don't really need our answers.
They just simply need our presence.
And when we are present,
atop on the shoulder, a handshake,
an encouragement, a message.
Sometimes that's the most loving thing that we could do.
And sometimes, I say, I say, I am not going to be there.
Tabihan lam naten, embrace them, put their hands around them
and tell them, I am here.
You are not going through this alone.
That's empathy.
We empathize with them in their joys and in their sadness.
Sinasabi naten that your joys matter to me.
And your pain matters to me.
And what you are going through matters to me.
This is what happens when we understand that we belong to one another.
So here's a simple challenge.
Who around you needs you to celebrate with them?
And who around you is hurting and simply needs you to be there?
Celebrate with them.
Cry with them.
Walk with them.
So when we love one another,
by empathizing with one another,
living in harmony,
living in harmony with one another,
Romans chapter 12 verse 16.
There are many ways we can live in harmony with one another.
But Paul points out one very specific way.
But we not so not in a new testament.
There are many ways when we could live in harmony with one another.
But in Romans chapter 12, Romans chapter 12,
he pinpoints a very specific way
when we can live in harmony with one another.
And that is by not looking at others lower than ourselves.
Paul points to one important attitude
that can destroy harmony and that is pride.
Pride makes us think I am better than you.
And when we think we are better than others,
we begin choosing whom we will accept, associate or even love.
I am saying I believe Pablo D. to do not think of yourselves as superior.
And so in the church and the faith group,
we don't look down on people because of their social status,
education, job, background, appearance, personality,
or what they can offer to us.
There should be no higher or lower people among us.
We all stand together under the grace of God.
And so manifestation is that we because of pride
and looking at others lower than us.
We may avoid people whom the world considers
an important, we don't welcome them.
Instead, we must include them, we associate with them,
we treat them with dignity and respect.
And that's what harmony looks like.
Don't look down on others, don't discriminate.
Don't think of yourself as better, welcome, and value everyone.
And because when we understand that we belong to one another,
therefore there is no room for superiority.
So we are not allowed to do anything.
Instead of taking revenge.
In the long-term thing, when we go to the Yung Tama,
Misan, we are in the place of one thing justice,
instead of taking revenge, we do what is right.
So I'll be put in the suburbs of 1780, 1990,
and Romans chapter 12.
Do not repay anyone evil for evil.
Be careful to do what is right in the eyes of everyone.
If it is possible as far as it depends on you,
live at peace with everyone.
Do not take revenge, my dear friends.
But leave room for God's wrath.
So what do we do when someone hurts us?
Sassim Bahan, Safayi Group or anywhere in the family,
they are not going to be a good thing.
We sometimes say things that we don't mean.
We hurt each other verbally or we do things
that people perceive as wrong or offensive.
We feel mistreated or someone may be doing something
literally against us.
Our natural response may be to get even.
And for him I must be braver because he is a fool of us.
No.
We can drive,
we can shout and we can shout
our politicians
because we lookama at Lang desperately.
He goes gather and donate.
So if we decide what to do,
we will make a fake relationship,
like everything we have done,
all kinds of things weleri ا
or whatever.
Through the pastries,
young ganona, galing anona, stata with papuntang fake fellowship,
alconfait sometimes in my head, Lord, gusto gusilang sagasāā'a.
At me, sateladati nuturau bino businā angu pasilā, green, green,
pakaionā sagasā angu hindi kukasālāna.
The urge in me to actually take revenge,
or that desire even the thought is something that God does not want.
Doing what is right instead of taking revenge.
Poses do not answer evil with more evil instead,
but it is right to do what is right.
And if it is possible, as far as it depends on you live at peace with everyone.
And let me pull weak and not control how people will respond to us,
but weak and always control how weak and respond to them.
As far as it depends on us, we choose peace.
And that's why Paul said, do not take revenge, mind your friends,
but leave room for God's wrath.
We do not need to take matters into our own hands,
and we can leave justice in God's hands,
but Paul goes even further.
It is not enough simply to avoid revenge.
We actively choose to do good.
Due to me, sateladā mahera patonāyadat we love one another.
He was an unimaginable man,
and said, as if he was a little bit of a fool,
and he was a fool,
and he was a fool.
And he was a fool,
but that's exactly what God is telling us,
because that is how we prove what true love is.
And that's why Paul says,
if your enemy is hungry, feed him,
if he is thirsty, give him something to drink.
But if he is thirsty,
he will be a good man.
But instead give them food and water to drink.
Instead of asking,
how can I get even,
we ask, what is the right thing,
and good thing to do?
Ayāyāsābīni pāblāsā verse 21,
do not be overcome by evil,
but overcome evil with good.
I'm going to say something which I hope you will remember.
When we repay evil with evil,
evil wins twice.
Let me say that again.
When we repay evil with evil,
evil wins twice.
They wrongdoing causes us to respond with wrongdoing.
But when we respond to evil,
by doing what is right, and good,
we refuse to let someone else as wrong,
determine the kind of person that we become.
This is the transformed life.
Don't get even,
choose peace,
read justice to God,
do good,
even to those who hurt you.
So,
how many people are going to say,
you are my own.
Who has offended you?
Sometimes we go to church,
and then as a family,
they say,
you are my family,
you are my parents,
and as a church,
husband or wife or children.
Sometimes it happens to us
that we go to church,
and our relationships may not be nice,
or our relationships in the faith,
group may not necessarily be an harmony.
Well,
if someone has hurt you or offended you,
what would it look like for you?
To choose what is right,
and good,
toward that person.
So Romans 12 shows us
that because of God's grace and mercy and cries,
the gospel transforms us from being self-centered
to other centered.
As our minds are renewed,
we grow in humility,
and we realize that we need each other,
and that we belong to one another.
This is what we call one another Christianity.
One another Christianity is marked by love.
So when we say,
we are not going to be able to remember this.
Loving one another means serving,
sharing,
empathizing,
living in harmony,
doing what is right.
Let us read the ways we love one another.
Loving one another is serving,
sharing,
empathizing,
living in harmony,
doing what is right.
I want you to look at that list.
Kai is a lampuja,
anpili in you.
Is it serving?
Serving the Lord,
and one another.
Is it sharing?
Sharing what you have?
Materials sharing?
Maybe the Lord is telling you,
hey, why don't you share?
Or share your home?
Your home doesn't have to be a mansion.
We are going to make a house
in the name of the name of the name of the name of the name of the name of the name of the name of the name of the name.
Share also words of blessing.
Maybe that's what you need to do.
Share words of blessing to someone.
Perhaps empathizing with someone.
You know somebody who is celebrating,
rejoicing,
but that person has nobody to rejoice with.
I don't know what I'm saying,
because I'm a church.
They actually have a reason to celebrate,
but they have no one to celebrate with.
Maybe the Lord has reminded you of someone right now.
Why don't you rejoice with that person?
Or maybe someone is going through hardship or pain?
Reach out, you know?
Empathize with him.
Living in harmony with one another.
Do not take revenge,
but instead do what is good.
Who may not have a son or may not have a son.
Do not take revenge.
Instead do what is good.
Finally doing what is right instead of taking revenge.
In short, serve, share, care,
live in peace, do good.
Anupujan, ungagarininu.
My question for you today is this.
Who is God asking you to love this who?
Who is God asking you to serve?
Who is God asking you to share with?
Who is God asking you to care for?
Meaning empathize with him.
Who is God asking you to live at peace with?
And who is God asking you to do good?
Unto.
Remember, loving one another is serving the Lord and one another.
It is sharing and blessing one another.
It is empathizing with one another.
It is living in harmony with one another.
It is doing what is right instead of taking revenge.
Who is God telling you to love this who?
Let's bow down our hands.
Let's close our eyes.
Let us pray.
Arunapasalatu, I am so thankful and blessed that you have brought your people here.
They have come here to show their love for you by being present.
But you, Lord Jesus, did not merely bring us to God.
You also brought us to be together.
And we do so by loving one another.
This is what one another Christianity is all about.
You did not intend for us to individually live in our own bubbles.
You meant us to become a part of each other.
And you are calling us to humble ourselves before you.
So that we will realize first and foremost that we cannot live and isolate in life.
We need to become a part.
We need to be involved.
We need to involve ourselves in others.
And when we do, you are calling us to love one another.
So you, Ikau, Apatil, Narinikmu Yungmen Saheb, Ikau, you are being called by the Lord.
To love others.
I want you to reflect.
Open your heart in your mind.
Who is God asking you to love this week?
Who is God asking you to serve?
Who is God asking you to share and bless something with?
Who is God asking you to care for?
To empathize with?
To rejoice and to mourn with?
Who is God asking you to live in peace?
And who is God asking you to do what is right?
Regardless of the hurt or the pain that other person may have caused to you.
You see, that's how God is calling you to show love to one another.
Maybe it's a member of your immediate family.
Maybe it's somebody in the workplace or school.
But maybe it's somebody in the church.
Maybe that person is in your faith group.
What God is asking you to do is to show one to others the love that you have received.
So Lord today I ask that you help all of us.
Now what is the reason for this?
That we are not an island to ourselves.
You have called us to be a part of each other.
So may we learn to love as we have received the same kind of love from you.
This is my prayer.
In Jesus name and let all of God's people say,
Amen.
And they praise the Lord.
If you not to walk on a poem of our ancestors,
let me just reiterate one of the things that I shared,
one of the ways when you show love to each other is by sharing and sharing materially.
Financially is one of the ways that you could do or show your love to the church.
Now Sabikwad the start of the service.
Ready Nabahayo.
Are you ready?
Not just to listen.
Are you also ready to put the word into practice.
What is the reason for this?
I am not a part of the faith fellowship.
Now what will you do?
One of the ways that you show your love to the church is by giving.
So I implore you guys.
I hope that today you will be able to show the kind of love that you have for this church by giving.
Giving generously, giving faithfully, giving cheerfully.
Let's bow down our heads, let's close our eyes today as we give.
Lord, you have spoken to us today.
My prayers that you will speak to each and every one here today.
May this be an opportunity for us to share and give to the church.
Lord, you have exhorted us to love one another,
to love the church and today,
and to help us to be able to share and give to each other.
I am a baby guy for your honor and for your glory in Jesus name.
And let all of God's people say, Amen.
Thank you.
Praise Jesus.
I hope we are blessed with the wonderful and powerful proclamation of God's Word.
May we believe this place and we sing our last song.
Let's come to the Lord and pray and let everyone to close their eyes and bow their heads.
Lord Jesus, Salamat Painon for bringing us all together here, Lord.
Salamat Lord for reminding us, Lord,
go and know ebics of being in love, not by the name of God.
Lord, He gets a lot of we are challenged, Lord God,
to represent your love, but the best name in Salamat, Lord.
And with that Lord, committed Muhammad,
committed upon Bavat, is a Lord Jesus.
Help us, Lord bless us to be pervellers of your love, Lord Jesus.
And it declare this Lord God, over all the lives of your people, Paminahon.
We surrender lives to you, Lord.
We commit our lives to you.
Hallelujah.
May the God of Hope fill you with all the joy and peace as you trust in Him.
So that you may overflow with hope by the power of the Holy Spirit.
May the Lord bless you and protect you.
May the Lord smile on you and be gracious to you.
May the Lord show you His favor and give you His peace.
Lord, we worship you, we surrender lives to you in Jesus' name we pray.
Amen. Amen.
Pala Panculadesi Jesus!
And let's sing this one last song.
Hallelujah.
Let's all together sing.
May the Lord bless you.
path of the Lord go high.
Amen.
Father, it's a good song.
That this close is in order.
Still I will say,
Blessed be the name of the Lord.
Blessed be the glory of the Lord.
Blessed be the name of the sunshine in down on me.
When the world saw that it should be.
Blessed be the name of the Lord.
And every blessing you pour out our turn back to grace.
Blessed be the glory of the Lord.
Blessed be the name of the Lord,
Blessed be the only
Blessed be the glory of His name.
You give them take away,
My heart will choose to say,
Lord, Blessed be the only
You give them take away,
Now you give them take away,
My heart will choose to say,
Lord, Blessed be the only
Blessed be the first one,
Blessed be the name of the Lord,
Blessed be the name.
Hallelujah, Jesus.
Blessed be the name of the Lord,
Blessed be the the only
Yes man, Blessed be the man of the Lord,
Blessed be the only man.
Blessed be the name of the Lord, Blessed be the glory of the Spirit.
You give and take away, You give and take away,
My heart will choose to say,
The Blessed be the glory of the Spirit.
You give and take away, You give and take away,
My heart will choose to say,
The Blessed be the glory of the Spirit.
Hallelujah!
See you next year, God bless you, Lord.